First, the cassava roots must be peeled.
Then they are grated with a grating machine, as can be seen here in the picture.
The grated mass falls into a container.
This mass is then put into a tipiti.
This is a sausage-like casing that is stretched by weight, reducing the circumference and thus squeezing out the juice.
The modern press as we know it is also known there.
After being squeezed in the tipiti, the cassava mass looks like a corn cob, but is very fluffy.
and can easily be passed through a sieve.
Impurities remain.
In the squeezed cassava juice, the so-called goma settles at the bottom, which is used for chewing gum, for example.
Finally, a fire is lit in the roasting oven.
and the dried cassava flakes are dried further on it and roasted for a shorter or longer period depending on the type of farinha.
By removing the cassava juice, the cassava, which was originally poisonous, becomes safe to enjoy.